The Irish army's forgotten battle
The Siege of Jadotville is a war, drama, thriller film directed by Richie Smyth.
Irish Commandant Pat Quinlan leads a stand off with troops against French
and Belgian Mercenaries in the Congo during the early 1960s.
Pat Quinlan, played by Jamie Dornan.
Rene Faulques, played by Guillaume Canet.
Conor Cruise O'Brien, played by Mark Strong.
Sgt. Jack Prendergast, played by Jason O'Mara.
General McEntee, played by Michael McElhatton.
Dag Hammarskjold, played by Mikael Persbrandt.
The Siege of Jadotville is a 2016 action-war film directed by
Richie Smyth and written by Kevin Brodbin.
An Irish-South African production, the film is based on Declan Power's book, The Siege at Jadotville: The Irish Army's Forgotten Battle (2005), about an Irish Army unit's role
in the titular Siege of Jadotville during the United Nations Operation in the Congo in September 1961, part of the Congo Crisis that stretched from 1960 to 1965.
First screened at the 2016 Galway Film Festival, the film received a
limited cinema distribution in Ireland in September 2016.
It had simultaneous worldwide distribution on Netflix and in a
number of US iPic Theaters during October 2016.
It won three Irish Film & Television Awards, including Best Director.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book,
bravery, congo, conflict, united nations.
The tone is emotional and intense.